Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org
No. Jijau.
You need not do that.
Bless the unborn. O Goddess Jagadamba!
Mother…
is Abasaheb home?
He's going to the court of the Nizam
and will meet you once he returns.
Lakhuji Raje!
The court of Nizam admires
your honor and glory.
Since the time
you've joined the Nizamshahi.
brave warriors have either bowed before it
or sought refuge under its protection.
Glory be to Allah!
The courage displayed by you
and your sons is remarkable.
You are honored with
a royal rank. elevated status.
and new lands.
Please accept.
Congratulations to you!
Salutations to Lord Shiva!
Abasaheb!
Hey!
When you were our foe.
your strength was a nightmare.
Now that you're a friend.
the thought of you joining the enemy
is even more terrifying.
I wish neither to live in fear
nor suffer under your wrath.
Salutations to Lord Shiva…
The backstabbing nature of your ilk!
The day the Marathas awaken to this truth
will mark the beginning of your end!
Dawn of the Marathas!
Shall we proceed?
Proceed where?
More attacks will follow.
More blood will be spilled.
More of our people will be massacred.
and their corpses will be
brought back here.
Then why proceed?
It's better to wait here
on the burning ghats.
I'll certainly seek
an explanation from the Nizam.
Raje. we are subjects of the Nizam.
The subjugated have no right
to question their rulers.
For those who serve.
dawn and dusk are all the same.
For the sake of self-respect.
I have often thought of
sacrificing everything
and rising in rebellion.
But the time is not right. Jija.
Waiting for the right time
has resulted in burning pyres in villages.
Tomorrow. villages will be
reduced to ashes!
Turmoil. havoc. and chaos everywhere
Great destruction is at work. God
The abode of yours stands devastated
How much more suffering must we endure?
O Lord!
Mahadeva!
Answer our anguished hearts. our prayers
Arise and protect your own abode
O Lord!
Mahadeva!
Answer our anguished hearts. our prayers
Arise and protect your own abode
Death to Pune! Death to Pune!
Pune is dead!
This punishment is imposed
due to Shahaji Raje Bhosale's
rebellion against the Adilshahi!
Henceforth. the provinces of Pune and Supe
shall remain under the Adilshahi rule.
By order. a donkey-drawn plough will be
driven across the unholy lands of Pune.
Pune is hereby declared an unholy land.
Settling and agricultural activities
are forbidden hereafter.
Festivals and celebrations
are declared unlawful.
Pune is dead!
Salutations to Lord Shiva!
Death to Pune! Death to Pune!
Pune is dead!
Can you see the destruction?
Or shall I show it to you?
This is my grandson.
This was once his paradise.
There was a beautiful courtyard here.
This is my son…
and this is my daughter-in-law.
I once called this place my home.
And this village. my family.
The village had a temple of yours.
But today. I've realized
even you couldn't help us!
We ran to you.
trusting you to protect our lives.
But even you were not safe here!
Oh. Mahadeva!
Can you not see our anguish?
Can you not hear
our desperate prayers?
Our fate is in your hands.
Can you not answer our desperate plea?
Oh. Mahadeva!
My God!
How much more bloodshed
do you want to see?
How much more destruction
Raje…
Either come to protect us.
or destroy us completely!
Either declare you can't protect us.
or prove your existence once and for all!
Oh. Lord! Oh. Mahadeva!
Raje…
Shambhu Raje!
What is the name of our beloved prince?
Shivaji!
- All hail Goddess Shivai!
- Victory to the Mother Goddess!
Raje…
Where is brother Shambhu?
Brother!
Brother. what are you looking at?
Those flags.
Brother. whose flag is that?
The Mughals'.
And the other one?
That is the Adilshahi flag.
And this one is ours. right?
No. This one belongs to the Nizamshahi.
Where is our flag?
We don't have a flag.
All of them sought Abasaheb's alliance
whenever it suited them.
Abasaheb first allied with the Mughals.
then with the Adilshahi.
and now he's with the Nizams.
Shivba…
whoever commands the flag rules the land.
Then why don't we command our own flag?
Swarajya is a prerequisite
for having your own flag.
And what is the prerequisite for Swarajya?
It's been two years.
My grand dream of Taj…
is waiting in hope.
Will my legacy remain an unfinished story?
May the Emperor remain safe and sound.
Your dream will come true. and your
legacy will stand at its pinnacle.
Six months have passed since
the siege of Mahuli Fort.
The Nizamshahi has no way forward.
Shahaji has neither the courage to rebel
nor the ability to negotiate.
The Nizamshahi is finished.
The Nizamshahi would have fallen long ago.
were it not for that wretched Shahaji.
Along with the Nizamshahi.
Shahaji must also be eliminated.
If prayers alone could solve a crisis.
we would never have been
in this situation.
The courageous men I assembled
were lost to famine.
I mustered a courageous rebellion.
but got discouraged
by the betrayal of my own people.
A secret conspiracy to seize control of
the Nizamshahi was hatched behind my back.
and now I stand besieged!
The eclipse is overtaking the sun. Jija.
Your Majesty! Adil Shah in the Deccan
and the Mughals in the North.
Between them lies the dying Nizamshahi.
Once the Nizamshahi is wiped out.
nothing will stand between
the Adilshahi and the Mughals.
The Adilshahi is incapable of withstanding
the wrath of the Mughal armies.
The Mughal army is a python.
swallowing everything in its path.
The Mughals could never threaten us.
due to the presence of a fierce warrior
in the Nizamshahi.
Shahaji Raje Bhosale!
We should secure his alliance before
the Mughals do. my King!
I approve!
I do not approve!
I refuse to become a vassal of Adil Shah.
I approve!
Shahaji must be treated as
the designated heir. not as a vassal.
Approved!
But our ancestral land.
Pune. must be returned.
Approved!
Send a message to Emperor Shah Jahan
that Shahaji Bhosale intends
to serve the Adilshahi.
I will never approve of this.
The Nizamshahi has been weakened
by both of us.
Now Adil Shah wishes
to enjoy the hunt alone.
Send him a message.
Both the Nizamshahi
and Shahaji will be destroyed.
Offer 50.000 gold coins
to Emperor Shah Jahan.
on the condition that
Shahaji Raje remains our ally.
Not 50.000.
Demand 100.000 gold coins.
Adil Shah can have Shahaji as his ally…
but Shahaji won't get Pune.
No compromise on Pune!
I accept the demand of 100.000 gold coins.
provided Shahaji keeps Pune
and his allegiance to us.
Demand 500.000 gold coins.
Shahaji can have Pune.
but he cannot reside there.
Five lakh gold coins?
I approve 500.000 gold coins!
The Marathas can be dealt with later.
The completion of the Taj
is of utmost priority.
It's better to keep Shahaji
away from the Sahyadris.
Glory be to Allah!
The world may forget. but I know…
that the fourth pillar of Shah Jahan's
wife's tomb
was contributed by His Majesty.
Don't worry. my dear.
I will build one for you as well.
Brother. what's the matter?
The Nizamshahi rule has ended.
Ripped apart by the Mughals and Adil Shah.
Does that mean we are independent now?
Not really.
Abasaheb has forged a new alliance
with the Adilshahi.
Brother. are we going to Pune?
- We are heading to Bangalore.
- Why?
It is a pact between Abasaheb and Delhi.
Does that mean Abasaheb is defeated?
Mother. are you crying?
No. dear. Nothing like that.
Are you missing home?
I miss home too.
but I don't feel like crying.
Only a woman can understand this pain.
Every woman has to leave
her home once in her life.
Twice in my case.
You'll know. my dear.
You'll understand once you grow up.
Raje…
Shivba!
Did you get hurt?
This is not right.
This wrestling is not fair.
My brother-in-law is much older
than my husband.
Sai…
training against a stronger opponent
breeds a fiercer warrior.
Sai. elders need to be respected too.
Oh. is it?
Brother…
did you get hurt?
Shambhu. a lack of vigilance
is how a winning battle is lost.
I have got a message for Shahaji.
Mind how you speak!
It's Shahaji Raje!
A little more audacity could've ended with
your tongue on my spear!
Such pride at such a young age.
Were this a battlefield.
I would have answered in kind.
- So be it! Consider this a battlefield!
- Shambhu Raje!
Shahaji…
Raje.
You've got a message from Bijapur.
This feels less like a message
and more like an assault.
We are just followers
of the Emperor's order. Shahaji Raje.
You are ordered to leave Bangalore.
And the court of Adil Shah
is waiting for you.
I will send my response.
- You may leave now.
- You are not getting it. Raje.
This fort…
this estate…
is no more under your control.
I am here to take you with me.
You have been summoned
by the court of Bijapur.
The order may be from Adil Shah.
but the words belong to another.
Who has been granted my estate?
Commander Afzal Khan Mohammad Shahi!
Rajaji…
I had sent you a message.
And what was your response?
"I am a king.
and I shall negotiate
only with the royal throne.
not its servant."
You and your arrogance!
I am willing to negotiate.
One kneels to beg for mercy.
not for negotiation.
Do you like elephants?
Please have mercy on my father.
No. I like lions.
Why?
A lion is the king of the jungle.
It's not afraid of anyone.
Wrong.
A lion fears an elephant
because the elephant knows its strength.
while the lion knows its limitations.
That is why a lion
changes its course in submission
when confronted by an elephant.
I beg you to have mercy on my father.
Your father could not save his fiefdom.
Let me see if you can save your father.
Before my elephant reaches yours.
if you can reach your father.
I shall spare all of you.
Run!
Father. we survived.
A lion rules the jungle
until an elephant declares itself king.
Note it down!
If a situation arises
with Afzal on one side
and all the brave hearts on the other.
and the Almighty is asked
who will conquer.
the universe will resonate…
Afzal…
Afzal!
Forgive me. Jija.
for making you go through
this situation again.
Rush to Pune at the earliest.
Our hard-earned estate
has been snatched from us.
Let's at least retain the rightful land.
I'm tired. Raje.
Generations have wasted their lives
under the burden of foreigners.
The next generation
must be its own master.
I have decided that once I reach Pune.
I will train both our sons
to fight for their rights.
Not both.
Shambhu…
will stay with me.
But. Raje…
I am sending a successor to Pune.
and Adil Shah must not be given that idea.
It is best to keep
Shivba and Pune as far from
Adil Shah's sight as possible.
And when shall we meet again?
Never leave your father alone.
Master the fuel of rage.
Do not let it burn you.
And it is your responsibility
to pacify Shivba.
Brother. why can't we all stay together?
Shivba…
sometimes a sacrifice of one generation
creates a legacy for the family.
- And--
- I don't understand this!
Promise me you will
come to Pune at the earliest.
Promise me!
I promise.
I will come to Pune.
Raje. we have arrived in Pune.
Hey. old lady.
The King is here.
Look who is back!
The King!
Everything of mine has been destroyed.
The temple has been vandalized.
Is the King aware of it?
Daughters. women. children. and men…
all were disgraced by evil men.
Is the King aware of it?
Someone. somewhere. gave the order…
and this land was desecrated
by a donkey-drawn plough.
Is the King aware of it?
This Dussehra.
good did not triumph over evil.
Instead. evil reduced
the village to ashes!
Is the King aware of it?
The one who gives me back my life
is my King.
He who protects the dignity of women
He who restores the sanctity
of the village is my King.
He is not my King!
An aspiring light of hope has emerged
Answering the agonizing call
Of the Sahyadris
The divine light of beloved Shivaji
Has emerged
He sanctified this sacred land with
A golden plough to ignite a new beginning
A courageous beginning blessed by Shakti!
History stands still to witness
The beginning of a golden era
On this auspicious day
Let it be known to the skies
The thunderous roar of beloved Shivaji
Hear the ballad of Shivaji's valor
O people!
A fierce sun rises
Ending thousand years of darkness
Rudra's avatar stands
The destroyer of injustice
Hail Shivrai!
When he wields his fierce sword
Roaring. "Hail Mahadeva"
Unleashing his valor
The enemy runs for life
Hail Shivrai!
He has set the enemies' camps on fire
Causing mayhem
To the invading sultanates
He raised a Hindavi challenge
Listen. O people!
The sacred dawn broke
Beholder of good fortune
Vowed for Swarajya!
Listen. O people!
The warrior blood poured
As an offer to Rudra!
Listen. O people!
Drum beats echoed
A thumping victory of Torna
The fort resonated with
The roar of victory
Listen. O people!
FORT TORNA
FORT KONDHANA
FORT RAJGAD
Jijau Saheb. my daughter Tulsa
was returning from the riverfront.
This man. Babaji Patil.
from Ranjha village molested her!
Forced himself on her.
She committed suicide out of shame!
I didn't murder her. mind you!
That means you admit to violating her.
Who the hell are you to ask?
Patil!
You are all subjects of Adil Shah.
and so am I.
I have done nothing different
from what Adil Shah's men do.
Lady Bhosale…
call this off.
Call this off right now.
Call off these theatrics.
Call this--
This is not Adil Shah's court.
This is Queen Mother Jijau's
seat of justice.
Patil!
Let it be known that whoever violates
the dignity of women in Swarajya
shall face the sword of Shivaji.
The enemy trembles at his thunderous kick
Hail Shivrai!
Cut off his legs
and display him at the crossroads!
Today. it's limbs.
Tomorrow. heads will be severed.
The rebellion of Shahaji's sons.
Shambhu and Shivaji.
is becoming intolerable. Your Majesty!
Both are causing great trouble.
We need to act against them. Your Majesty.
When a bird settles for safety.
it surrenders the sky.
Krushnaji Baji is entrusted as
the Chandrarao of the Jawali estate.
The Jawali seat will
forever remain grateful to Swarajya…
Shivba Raje!
Father!
A new Chandrarao
has been designated in Jawali.
Is it really necessary
to bring up this minor issue now?
It's not as simple as you think. Father.
This time. Shahaji's son Shivaji
has appointed the Chandrarao.
Shahaji's son appears
equally eager to revolt!
Even though they have inherited
a rebellious nature…
failure is written in their destiny.
Shahaji's sons have come of age.
Look who is here
Causing the mayhem
He is Shambhu!
The fearless. Rudra's avatar
All hail Shambhu!
Shambhu!
When will your habitual interference
in state affairs end?
I've heard Adil Shah
aspires to conquer the world.
When did Bijapur's politics descend
to the level of children's play?
Along with your body.
your ego has also grown.
But your wisdom does not match your age.
Don't forget. just like me.
you are also subservient to Adil Shah.
Subservience is your nature.
Shambhu!
Bhosales are rulers!
And under our rule.
everyone is free to practice
their own dharma.
A ludicrous weapon.
yet the attitude of a warrior?
Protecting dharma with a bamboo stick?
Look who is here
Causing the mayhem
He is Shambhu!
The fearless. Rudra's avatar
All hail Shambhu!
Shambhu himself is a lethal weapon
in the protection of dharma.
Shambhu!
Be thankful it's a bamboo stick
in my hand.
not a sword!
Disobedience will be considered
a revolt against the Adilshahi.
Remember. the rebel has a name.
Sambhaji Shahaji Raje Bhosale.
Shambhu!
- May the Emperor of Bijapur…
- Live long!
Wait!
His Majesty's health is in decline.
Announce only news that brings relief.
The news pertains to Siva from the Deccan.
How can there be any bad news
about Siva?
Announce it.
Along with Kondhana Fort.
Siva has captured Purandar Fort
as well. Your Majesty.
His Majesty has himself declared
that the kid is still naive.
Just ignore him.
Then the naive kid captured more forts.
along with Purandar Fort.
The Jawali seat. which had
obeyed Bijapur's decree to date.
was candidly assigned
its own Chandrarao by Siva.
Well. doesn't matter.
How can we expect intellect
from a naive kid?
Siva in the Deccan and Shambhu in
the South are uniting the Hindu rulers.
But never mind.
His Majesty is more concerned about
innocent birds than the naive rebels.
Even the birds must be feeling
what an incredible pet king we have!
Neither does he soar.
nor does he let us take flight.
Fariyad Khan! Drag Shambhu
to this court right now!
Muse Khan. Fateh Khan!
Go and eliminate Siva
and all signs of his Swarajya!
- Go!
- Yes. Your Majesty.
Right now!
Raje…
Victory is ours!
Attack!
Raje…
- Glory to Bhavani!
- Glory to Shivaji!
Then why don't we command our own flag?
Swarajya is a prerequisite
for having your own flag.
And what is the prerequisite for Swarajya?
Rebellion.
Raje…
Henceforth. our land
will hoist only our flag!
We have not just unfurled the saffron
flag. but ignited a revolution!
Let it be known to the arrogant tyrants.
The Marathas have ceased
to bow down to foreigners!
This revolution is for my motherland!
This revolution is for
command over our own flag!
This revolution is for self-respect!
And this revolution is for Swarajya!
- Glory be to…
- Lord Mahadeva!
Raje is here!
On this beautiful occasion of a wedding
Graced by kin and kith
Beautifully adorned groom has arrived
To tie the sacred knot
Gentle. nervous. and blushing bride
She has arrived. beautifully adorned
Courteous and shy
Naive. virtuous. expressive eyes
Longing to take a glimpse
The moment has arrived
My life is graced by your presence
As Goddess Laxmi
She has arrived at this golden moment
Such a fortunate and auspicious moment
Sai. being a Kshatriya's
life partner is not easy.
Being in the company of the Bhosales
is like walking on the edge of a sword.
I'm aware.
Please proceed with the vows.
Walking on the edge of a sword
is no challenge for me.
I am blessed
With a bond of seven lives
My life is graced
With a beautiful Paarijaat flower
I am blessed
With a bond of seven lives
My life is graced
With a beautiful Paarijaat flower
I am blessed
With a bond of seven lives
What did you pray for?
It must not be revealed.
Turmeric for the wounds.
I don't even have a minor scratch.
Let me see!
Here. and here. and over here.
There will always be traces of soil
on a farmer's body.
Doesn't it burn?
Your scolding burns more.
No way! Enough joking!
Sai!
Isn't it a lucky day
to receive Paarijaat flowers?
I am so blessed.
Don't they belong to you?
The Paarijaat may belong to a courtyard.
but it blooms across the neighborhood.
I may belong to you.
but my destiny is with Swarajya.
Hey…
how did you get injured?
Didn't notice it in the hustle.
Where's the turmeric?
Are you aware of it. dear?
People are celebrating your valor
all over Swarajya.
Salutations to Mahadeva
Shivaji. the incarnation of Mahadev
Has risen on the Sahyadris
Fierce warriors with iron fists
Have unleashed lethal swords
And blazing spears
O valiant beam of light
Beacon of bravery
You ended the age of darkness
O pillar of Ram Rajya
Founder of Hindavi Swarajya
You are the one adored
You eliminated the unrighteous evils
Challenged the invaders
O progenitor of new era
Lead us to unity
And guide us to achieve your vision
The one and only one. zenith of valor
O Chhatrapati
O epitome of bravery. virtuous
Upholder of dharma. O Chhatrapati
O pride of Marathas
O tiger of Mother Goddess Bhavani
O legend of legends. righteous
Guardian of principles. O Chhatrapati
O fierce warrior
Crown jewel of Kshatriyas. O Chhatrapati
O pride of Marathas
O tiger of Mother Goddess Bhavani
You vowed to protect
The gods. nation. dharma
And sacred duties with your blood
You are the torchbearer
To end the age of darkness
With clasped palms
You bow to the saints. sages. and monks
Severed the limbs of traitors
Who looked down upon the Swarajya
Shattering the chains of caste
Guarding the common good
You rose as our savior
The world has known a thousand kings
But my heart bows to the one alone
Chhatrapati Shivrai
Bestow your grace upon us
Grant us strength to guard
The soul to die for you
O Chhatrapati
The one and only one. zenith of valor
O epitome of bravery. virtuous
Upholder of dharma. O Chhatrapati
O pride of Marathas
O tiger of Mother Goddess Bhavani
O legend of legends. righteous
Guardian of principles. O Chhatrapati
O fierce warrior
Crown jewel of Kshatriyas. O Chhatrapati
O pride of Marathas
O tiger of Mother Goddess Bhavani
From the heart of Maval
Devotees and locals alike came
Seeking a glimpse of the divine
The mere sight of him
Is ultimate contentment
I'm blessed to worship my King Shivaji
The premise garlanded
Adorned and illuminated
To celebrate this auspicious day
The euphoric moment of Shivba's sight
Has filled my heart with blissful tears
To bow in worship
And prostration at this divine moment
Is a blissful fortune
To raise the revered saffron high
And to paint the skies with its glory
Grant us a life of your devotion
A death of valor in your honor
The one and only one. zenith of valor
O Chhatrapati
O epitome of bravery. virtuous
Upholder of dharma. O Chhatrapati
O pride of Marathas
O tiger of Mother Goddess Bhavani
O legend of legends. righteous
Guardian of principles. O Chhatrapati
O fierce warrior
Crown jewel of Kshatriyas. O Chhatrapati
O pride of Marathas
O tiger of Mother Goddess Bhavani
Your Majesty. our forces couldn't
hold their ground against Siva.
Muse Khan has also been killed.
What about Shambhu?
Your Majesty!
Shambhu wasn't flaunting
the bamboo stick this time.
What was he wielding?
Look who is here
Causing the mayhem
He is Shambhu!
The fearless. Rudra's avatar
All hail Shambhu!
Shambhu!
Look who is here
Causing the mayhem
He is Shambhu!
The fearless. Rudra's avatar
All hail Shambhu!
Shambhu!
Dogs have been sent to hunt the tiger!
Shahaji's sons have
traumatized Bijapur's armies.
His Majesty's grandeur has doubled.
The smile on his face is obvious.
My love!
Those who refuse to wear anklets
end up chaining their own feet.
All that matters
is the sound of the bells.
Taming a wild elephant is
mere child's play for you.
Your Majesty. the Adilshahi
possesses only one elephant.
Afzal!
Of course!
Shahaji Raje Bhosale…
hope you had a safe journey.
The Adilshahi's famed hospitality
is nothing new to me.
The Mughals. the Nizams.
and the Adilshahi
have long held a disgraceful habit
of dishonoring the loyal.
The progenitor of rebels
now speaks of loyalty.
Shahaji Raje. commander
of the Adilshahi Empire…
tell me.
What have you done
to crush the rebels of the empire?
I tried to dissuade them
in every possible way.
But needless to say…
princes these days
hardly heed their fathers.
You are very well aware
of the consequences of disobedience.
I hope you will accept
the punishment as well.
I have heard that
the Adilshahi armies were sent
to stop Shambhu and Shivaji.
I have received no further details
about it to date.
My loyalty to the Adilshahi
still stands firm.
Imprison this puppet of loyalty!
Mother. will Abasaheb be released?
Where is Shivba?
Shivba!
Brother Shambhu!
You carry Abasaheb's persona within you.
They have set a condition
to return Fort Kondhana.
We don't need to agree to anything.
If you receive any message.
maintain the same response.
How are we supposed to free Abasaheb?
By striking Bijapur with lightning speed.
storming the prison.
and securing his release.
It's not that easy.
One mistake. and we are doomed.
I know the Adilshahi playbook inside out.
Every passing day in confinement
is a threat to Abasaheb's life.
Give me some time to think over it.
Shivba…
we are running short of time.
How is Ausaheb?
She thinks of you all the time.
And what about you?
How have you been. Shivba?
Do you remember your promise?
I am coming to Pune.
Tell Ausaheb that
I long to be fed by her once again.
Be prepared to march towards Bijapur!
Yes. my King.
Send a message to Emperor Shah Jahan
through Prince Murad Baksh.
Yes. my King!
Father. the Marathas have sent
a plea for support.
Perhaps Adil Shah has succeeded
in suppressing the rebellion.
Captive Shahaji has neither
lost his self-respect
nor the fierce pride in his eyes.
Pardon my audacity. my Queen.
but showing mercy to a traitor
is an invitation to future betrayal.
Afzal. the jungle follows only one rule.
Kill the prey at first sight.
Emperor Shah Jahan
has yet to respond. my King.
Brother Shambhu won't wait any longer.
Shambhu!
Shahaji Raje is being held
in the northern underground prison.
My King! Shahaji Raje is being
escorted into the royal court.
Adil Shah intended to counter us
with the help of Shahaji.
With the aid of Siva.
we will now destroy Adil Shah.
"Shivaji Raje Bhosale is a close
confidant of the Mughal Empire.
Emperor Shah Jahan decrees that
the well-being of his father.
Shahaji Raje Bhosale. who remains
in your captivity. must be ensured.
Any harm done to him
would be considered a direct
challenge to the Mughal Empire.
Wise judgment shall decide
our next response."
You are extremely fortunate.
When Shah Jahan wanted to kill you.
Adil Shah saved your life.
Now that the Adilshahi
poses a threat to your life.
Shah Jahan is asking for your well-being.
Abasaheb.
Shambhu Raje!
Kudos to the Bhosales' spies!
Shahaji Raje is yet to be released.
and Shambhu has already
arrived to receive him.
His release was inevitable today.
Be grateful the reason is you. not me.
You have nurtured arrogance
within your sons.
But we possess the means
to tame arrogance.
Shahaji Raje Bhosale…
you shall be released.
but under one condition.
Fort Kondhana is yours.
Shivba will hand it over.
Shahaji. your reputation as
a master strategist is well-renowned.
Earlier. you captured my territories.
And now. you are hijacking my words too?
Very well.
You've guessed the first condition.
The second condition is my prerogative.
Shambhu Raje. from today onward.
you will serve the Adilshahi.
And you will serve under
Afzal Khan's command.
Agreed.
Shambhu…
that was hasty.
No father should endure confinement
for so many days.
I guess I arrived late. Abasaheb.
The Emperor of Bijapur has always
had respect for your stature. Shambhu.
But ultimately.
he placed you under my servitude.
The emperor may have
doubts about your capability.
That is the reason
for appointing a Maratha.
Shambhu Raje. I'll lead the attack.
Aapa Khan may attempt
to escape from the other side.
Until then. hold on to this position.
Commander. I will lead the attack.
You hold on to this position.
Must you be stubborn every single time?
If victory is a necessity.
stubbornness is a prerequisite.
This campaign is under my command.
Obey the order of command.
An order is a king's privilege.
Sadly. you are not a king.
Despite your prayers
and my unrelenting efforts.
why is the ultimate goal eluding us. Baba?
Tell me. what falls short here?
Your prayers or my efforts?
You are a mere slave
of the King's order. Afzal.
Destiny favors only those
who follow their own command.
Shambhu!
A mere title does not make one
a true King.
The Marathas are destined either to die…
or live in slavery.
The day the Marathas conquer.
a true King shall rise.
No matter how many battles you win.
you are still destined to remain a slave.
Brother Shambhu!
I couldn't keep the promise
of coming to Pune. Shivba.
My heart is torn apart!
You are the only savior. O Jagadamba!
Leaving my life a drift in darkness
He has gone never to return
My brother. Sambha
Little Shivba was graced
By mother's warmth
Separation was in fate
He was in a far away lands
My brother. Sambha
My heart and soul was in far away lands
And my eyes were longing for him
I was yearning for his glimpse since long
My Sambha
Beloved brother of Shivba
And a piece of my heart
My beloved prince
My beloved. King Sambha
Hold him close to your heart
Feed him with your love
Shower him with your love
Like your own. O Jagadamba
My Sambha
He was impulsive.
Stubborn.
Free-spirited!
Had I spent more time with him.
I would have tempered his nature.
He promised to share a meal with me.
My eyes were longing for him.
That promise won't be fulfilled now.
Who caused this. Shivba?
Afzal Khan.
Promise to bring me Afzal's head. Shivba.
My heart and soul was in far away lands
And my eyes were longing for him
I was yearning for his glimpse since long
My Sambha
Hold him close to your heart
Feed him with your love
Shower him with your love
Like your own. O Jagadamba
My Sambha
My King.
My King!
The scribe of the Mahabaleshwar basin.
Rango Trimal. molested a girl. my King.
The punishment should have
preceded the report!
Cut off his limbs!
The coward has taken refuge in Jawali.
Send a message to the Chandrarao
and get him arrested immediately.
Do not bury a burning issue
under the ashes of silence!
You will face the wrath of fury!
Speak up!
My King…
The Chandrarao himself
has given him refuge.
The Jawali seat remains
forever grateful to Swarajya.
Shivba Raje!
The Chandrarao needs to be
controlled. my King.
He is taxing merchants
within our own territory.
Absconders of Swarajya are
living with impunity in Jawali.
He is under the illusion
that he is a king.
I had wished for the Chandrarao
to be part of Swarajya.
The strategic territory of Jawali
I ignored his increasing meddling.
But the Chandrarao seems
to be in a total delusion.
Pant!
Send a message to the Chandrarao.
asking him to come out of his delusion.
Any empathy shown to him is only
because of Aausaheb's promise.
One should not proclaim the benefits
and generosity extended to anyone.
but make him realize
by whose grace he proclaims the seat!
No one can proclaim themselves a King
by gathering a gang.
Jawali is my ancestral territory.
Sri Mahabaleshwar has
bestowed the grace of Jawali upon me.
I have the Emperor's support.
Unwanted interference
will not go unanswered.
Prove your valor today itself.
Why wait for tomorrow?
Come today itself.
The arms and ammunition are ready to fire.
So be it!
Hail Shivrai!
Chandrarao…
I heard that Shivaji
is marching towards us!
He's coming.
Don't worry.
Why fear when I am here?
Chandrarao. refuge in Jawali
is the only reason I'm still alive.
Otherwise. my amputation was definite!
But suppose he actually arrives here…
- then what?
If he comes here…
your name will be engraved in history.
My name? How come?
Let me explain.
Rango Trimal compelled
Shivaji to come to Jawali.
and Chandrarao killed him.
You mean he wouldn't dare
step inside Jawali.
Raje. Shivaji has invaded Jawali
with his men!
You need not worry.
Is invading Jawali a cakewalk?
Let him come.
It would be an achievement for him
just to reach Jambhul Valley.
Raje. they have crossed Jambhul Valley
and are storming through Saapla Pass.
Hail Shivrai!
Raje!
News has been confirmed. Shivaji Raje
has been spotted at Daabhiltok!
Hail Shivrai!
You need not worry.
It will take him at least six hours
to reach from Daabhiltok.
Raje…
Shivaji is nowhere to be seen.
No further reports of his sighting.
Didn't I tell you?
He must have gotten scared.
- You need not worry--
- Keep your mouth shut. Pratap!
He's not going back alive today!
Hey! Take your positions!
Rango Trimal!
It's time to engrave
your name in history!
Raje…
Pratap!
Salutations to Mahadeva!
Now!
Move quickly! Attack him!
Raje…
Your gracious invitation compelled me
to present myself today itself.
Mercy. my King!
Please forgive me!
I beg for mercy.
You must consider the Adilshahi
before harming me.
Shivaji was not born
to think about the Adilshahi.
But the Adilshahi shall never forget
how I absolved your sins.
Chandrarao…
you've inherited the legacy
of Chandrarao More.
Yet you flaunt the shackles
of invaders like ornaments?
Across Nizamshahi. Adilshahi.
and Mughal rule.
servility to invaders
has stifled this land!
By trampling the invaders.
I aspire to Hindavi Swarajya.
And what did I ask for in return?
I expected your bonding with Swarajya.
You despise being enslaved by invaders.
What's wrong with me rejecting yours?
Swarajya demands loyalty.
not slavery. Chandrarao!
"Swarajya" means…
our land. our resources. our hard work.
and the prosperity of all the people.
"Swarajya" means our efforts.
our will. our aspirations.
and collective success.
"Swarajya" means our native.
our culture. our belief.
and self-respect of the people.
I expected a supporter in you. but you
turned into an opposer. Chandrarao.
Salutations to Mahadeva!
This is the dawn of true justice
in Jawali under Swarajya.
Jawali shall henceforth be
part of Swarajya. Chandrarao.
Salutations to Mahadeva!
Your Majesty!
Jawali's Chandrarao.
Krushnaji Baji is no more.
You take over as the new Chandrarao.
Your Majesty. that's not possible.
Why?
Shivaji attacked Jawali
and killed Chandrarao.
And now he has declared
a new King of Jawali.
Shivaji Raje Bhosale himself.
What do we name our prince?
Sambhaji.
Sambhaji!
My Shambhu!
Good wishes for the commemoration
of the Bijapur court.
Commemoration of Jawali.
Siva has gained total control over
all the affairs and trade of Jawali
within three years.
The entire Konkan.
down to every corner. has turned saffron.
And what are the achievements
of the veterans present here?
Nothing but consorting
with the courtesans of Bijapur.
Late Mohammad Adil Shah
mistook Siva for being naive.
I will not repeat that mistake.
If the wrists are reluctant
to wield a sword…
they should be adorned with bangles.
It's easy to be audacious
in the court. Afzal.
Even the rocks of the Sahyadris
strike back.
My Queen. please rest assured.
Muse Khan went with the same instincts.
He never came back.
but news of his fate did.
How horrific you want Siva's end to be
depends only on your order.
Shall he be dragged in chains
like his father.
or shall I send him
to Allah like his brother?
My King. Afzal has resolved to kill you.
Setting out on a new campaign. Afzal?
This time. I am on a campaign
to change my destiny. Baba.
Destiny is Allah's will. Afzal.
All you need to do is
rid yourself of arrogance.
Arrogance seldom matters
to mighty warriors. Baba.
I am here to seek your blessings.
not your advice.
The path you have chosen
calls for advice. not blessings.
Your arrogance will decide. Afzal.
whether you create history.
God willing.
or become part of history.
Will I emerge triumphant. Baba?
Allahu Akbar.
Allahu Akbar…
Will I emerge triumphant. Baba?
Bad omen!
- Bad omen!
With no festival or celebration today.
what has brought the harem here?
- You are heading for the expedition--
- I am a veteran of numerous expeditions…
but never been treated
with such pomp before.
We just wanted to bid farewell to you.
This farewell reeks of fear.
May I know the reason?
Her Highness was saying…
What was she saying?
Peer Baba didn't answer clearly.
I'll give a clear answer.
You're being secretive with me. Sai.
I'm concerned about your health.
I have spoken to the Rajvaidya.
He said that your health
is deteriorating day by day.
I'm worried about you. Sai.
I'm worried about you too. Raje.
But I do not need a Rajvaidya
to know your well-being.
You've weathered extreme storms.
What worries you now?
Sai…
what is coming is not a storm.
It's an apocalypse.
A brutal. unpredictable apocalypse.
Your Highness!
The deity is moved out of the temple!
I thought I would meet
your deity Vitthal before Siva.
Where is your deity Vitthal?
Hey!
Vitthal grants his divine sight
only at his own will!
Submit yourself in prostration.
and you'll be graced with the divine sight
of Vitthal and our King Shivaji as well!
My King. Khan has unleashed terror
in Pandharpur.
He's vandalizing all the temples
in his path…
desecrating the deities.
How many forts and pilgrim houses
are there on his route?
Five.
Raje. intimidating orders are being
sent to all the landlords of Maval.
I. Afzal Khan Mohammad Shahi.
the new commander of Wai.
wish to warn the people of Maval
that Siva has challenged the Adilshahi
by illegally capturing the Empire's forts.
Those who support disobedience
will forfeit their lands
and be punished with death.
Bear in mind…
no mercy will be shown to those
who support the rebellion.
- Kanhoji…
- Yes?
rush to Pune at the earliest.
Shivba needs your support.
Be his trusted companion.
Certainly.
Your Highness!
We. the chieftains of Maval. along with
our armies. are at your service.
Whoever we sought help from
has fallen at Afzal Khan's feet.
Mambaji Bhosale has also followed Khan.
Pandhare has also joined Khan's rank.
Kharate has refused to reciprocate.
Kalyanrao Jadhav is yet to respond.
My entire harem could not bring me
as much joy as all of you have.
May Allah grant them
the highest place in heaven.
The very ones we empowered
have now joined forces with Afzal.
They deserve to be punished. my King.
Self-interest has consumed them.
Swarajya is my aspiration.
It seems like a lonely battle.
Is there a place for me
in your grand aspiration. Shivba?
Salutations. my King!
Uncle Kanhoji. have you lost your way?
You too must have received Khan's order.
Shivba…
I'm here with a promise to Shahaji Raje.
That may be true.
Today. you may have joined me
to support me…
but the moment Khan reaches your lands…
you will retreat.
You will retreat
once he reaches your possessions.
My King…
So. it's better to retreat
right now. Uncle Kanhoji.
I won't take it to heart.
My King?
The Jedhe bloodline is not one
to betray. but to honor loyalty.
Who cares about Khan?
He may offer us land. money. and wealth.
but I despise wealth built upon
the trampling of my culture.
Shivba…
thousands of inspiring stars
may fade into darkness.
but an aspirational sun like you
must rise to dawn upon a new era.
And…
Shivba. henceforth…
I renounce all my lands. wealth.
possessions. and these five sons…
for the cause of Swarajya.
Uncle Kanhoji…
I counted on many.
but only you came.
I may be the only one right now.
but lakhs will follow you soon.
I hope they rise up to the challenge.
They are marching closer
towards Rajgad. my King.
Khan's forces continue to strengthen
as more chieftains join him.
- Bahirji!
- Yes?
Be prepared to leave Rajgad.
Pardon me. my King.
but this is a misstep.
If you leave and Afzal arrives here.
our capital will be in danger.
Tanaji. battles must be
avoided near homelands.
It is better to hold them on a frontier.
If he besieges the capital by brute force.
it will be a threat to Swarajya.
And make no mistake…
Afzal's pursuit is directed at me.
not at Swarajya.
May I ask you something?
Is something weighing on your mind?
You should express yourself.
Internal turbulence troubles
more than external storms.
Let it be.
Let me express my feelings to you.
You have much to accomplish ahead.
I might be a hurdle in your endeavors.
Though I wish to. I'm unable
to keep pace with your pursuit.
Continue pursuing your aspirations.
After all…
the shadows of those who run
toward the sun are often left behind.
I'm content to remain behind you.
I'm worried about you. Sai.
What concern is a wick.
if it burns itself
to ignite the torch of Swarajya?
Why shouldn't I be content with this life?
In difficult times.
you stood by me as Lord Rama.
Brightened my life with joy
during times of sorrow.
Just imagine.
I reached my destiny without much effort.
It brings me happiness
that you are in my life.
But I must confess a regret.
I could not spend my life with you.
a wish that remains unfulfilled.
Why speak as though
we are parting forever. Sai?
Avoiding an eventuality won't
stop it from happening. Raje.
Shall I tell you what I prayed for?
It must not be revealed.
If so…
I won't be able to express myself ever.
I prayed for…
this land to be blessed with Swarajya
through your hands.
For all your wishes
and aspirations to come true.
I'm content with this life.
knowing that Swarajya is your first love.
But in the next life.
I will not let anyone
take you away from me.
And in that life…
I won't accept anyone
else being part of your life.
Sai…
All my other lifetimes are yours.
Only yours.
O beloved Paarijaat
My life is graced by your presence
As a celestial star
As a pearl of the ocean
You have lit up my heart
Father… Siva has escaped to Jawali.
Jawali is a vast territory.
Where might Siva be hiding?
He has built a fort there.
Pratapgad.
Pratapgad!
Your presumption was spot on. Raje.
Khan has changed his course.
He is en route to Jawali via Wai.
What's your next move. Raje?
We do not possess an army strong
enough to face Khan's brute force.
nor do we have the time to raise one.
Our fate is your command.
O Mother Bhavani!
Jagadamba!
Father. this unrelenting rain
won't let us move ahead.
Shall we halt the army here for today?
This is the ultimate test
of the Sahyadri rains.
It will not recede
for another three months.
Camp the armies here in Wai!
Raje. Mother Goddess blessed us!
The rains have answered our prayers.
Khan is forced to camp in Wai.
Khan is compelled to camp.
but he won't stay quiet.
Unleash such hellfire across the Deccan
that even the Sahyadri rains
cannot douse it.
Your Highness.
Krushnaji…
head to Pratapgad
and deliver a message to Siva.
The rat must be forced to come out.
Yes. Your Highness.
Any message from Afzal?
No. my Queen.
Your Highness. Supe stands deserted.
The fort has been abandoned.
Not even a trace of a soldier.
Is there any response from Siva?
No. Your Highness.
Commander. we have captured both
the forts of Shirwal and Saswad.
They lost their nerve
before your forces even arrived.
Is there any response from Siva?
No. Father.
Your Highness! The forts of Tala.
Koppal. and Maval stand deserted.
We captured them
without a single shot fired.
Fazal. is there any response from Siva?
We do have a message.
but it is from the Queen.
Honorable Afzal Khan!
I believe you are relentless
in your pursuit.
Bijapur is abuzz with expectations.
The markets are abuzz
with wagers on how you'll seize Siva.
Every nook and corner
is abuzz with debate.
The court is eager to meet you
and hear tales of your bravery.
But your approach is commendable.
Neither any report nor any messages.
It appears you shall return
with a grand victory.
Granting supplies for the third time
for your convenience.
May this encourage you
in the steps to come.
Veiling venom in sweetness is an art
best learned from a woman.
Your Highness!
I am grateful you arrived
before the Queen could deride me again.
Krushnaji. explain every detail
thoroughly. I wish to know everything.
Pantaji Gopinath was ready
to receive me at Pratapgad.
Welcome.
Torrential rain is a unique
characteristic of our territory.
When can I expect to meet Shivaji Raje?
Soon.
You will meet him very soon.
Take some rest for a while.
It was unusual.
Everyone appeared to be busy
with their routine.
But. Your Highness.
I have a keen eye for the unusual.
Warm water was frequently taken
inside behind closed doors.
The air was filled with
the smell of a variety of herbs.
Krushnaji. get some rest.
- Please rest.
- Sure. but…
I sent multiple requests
to meet with Shivaji Raje.
I kept a close eye on every detail.
Warm water was delivered
at regular intervals.
and sounds of grinding
and crushing could be heard.
Did you meet Siva or not?
I did. Your Highness.
but after three days of waiting.
My King.
He hid his trembling hands
beneath the quilt.
but my sharp gaze missed nothing.
The fatigue in his eyes was
clearly visible. Your Highness.
Afzal Khan Mohammad Shahi.
the Adilshahi's most esteemed commander.
has set up camp for your meeting.
He has sent this letter for you.
Siva. I regard your father.
Shahaji Raje. as a brother.
I have enormous respect for him.
And you are like a nephew to me.
I will not take away the forts you have
seized from the Bijapur Sultanate.
I'm a large-hearted person.
All your acts of disobedience
shall be forgiven as well.
Come to meet me. Siva.
I'm eager to meet you
and embrace you in my arms.
What was his response?
Absolute silence.
Such insolence!
He dared to ignore my gesture?
He's sent an envoy. Your Highness.
Your Highness.
I am Pantaji Gopinath Bokil.
I come bearing a response
from Shivaji Raje.
Your Highness. Shivaji Raje is fortunate
that you consider him as one of yours.
My King…
I would not be able to say that.
You will have to.
Speak the words I ask you to.
Your Highness. the stories of your might…
Everything we've heard is absolutely true.
Shivaji Raje bows neither to the Mughal
forces nor to the armies of the Adilshahi.
He believes there is one
and only one stalwart in Bijapur.
Commander Afzal Khan!
Please come to Jawali.
Shivaji Raje extends an earnest request.
Pant!
I will never go to Jawali.
Your Majesty. you're committing a blunder.
You should seek an earliest
meeting with Commander Khan.
His desire is to undo the injustice
inflicted upon your family.
In fact. he is planning a grand welcome
for you at the Bijapur court.
What did he say?
Your Highness.
it is shameful to express…
but our King…
Our King is scared of you.
He has already offended you for no reason.
And now. fearing a visit with you.
he's spending sleepless nights.
Write this down as well.
Pant!
Bring Siva here!
I am no fool to set foot in Jawali.
Has Afzal made the Sahyadris his home?
Commander Khan
has requested more supplies.
My King.
It's been over a month.
We will have to respond.
Is there any response from Siva?
Kavji. have we received
any message from Uncle Kanhoji?
No. Father.
No. my King.
Pant!
Afzal must be drawn
into the depths of Jawali.
Absolutely impossible.
Commander Khan must come to Jawali
to resolve this deadlock. Krushnaji.
Listen. Pant…
Commander Khan has encamped here
with a vast armament.
How can we expect him to leave it
all behind and come alone?
Commander Khan can come
aptly decorated with his armament.
Raje is very keen to meet up.
But you must come to Jawali.
Who is he?
Bada Sayyad.
Has Shivba responded?
No. Raje.
Shivaji Raje has refused to meet.
Your Highness.
The Queen has sent a message.
If the wrists are reluctant
to wield a sword…
they should be adorned with bangles.
Pant!
I will come to Jawali!
Make it easy for him to reach Jawali.
Raje. Khan has agreed
to meet Shivaji Raje.
Afzal is a devious backstabber.
Be prepared with the armies.
My King!
We have received
grievous news from Rajgad.
So blessed
I am to be wedded to Shivaji
I'm content with this life.
knowing that Swarajya is your first love.
But in the next life.
I will not let anyone
take you away from me.
O beloved Paarijaat
My life is graced by your presence
As a celestial star
As a pearl of the ocean
You have lit up my heart
Checkpoints and guards have been set.
But. my King. comparatively.
we are deficient in military strength.
My King. Jedhe is here.
Salutations. my King!
You came alone.
but I'm glad you came.
I haven't come alone. my King.
My King.
They have left their homes
to embrace martyrdom.
If one is asked what a warrior
with no fear of death looks like.
let them be known as
the fearless faces gathered here.
Who are we fighting for?
For whom have all of you assembled here?
For yourself?
For Uncle Kanhoji?
Or for me?
Let me tell you.
For the smiling faces of those
you leave behind each morning.
this fight is for them.
We will have to ride the winds
and sacrifice our lives.
but this fight is for the commoners
on whose strength
the saffron stands proudly.
This fight is for the powerless
who aspire to fight but cannot.
The sacred land that blesses our crops.
The sacred land that
nurtures our children.
The Adilshahi commander. Afzal Khan.
with his mighty elephantry. cavalry.
huge army. and heavy artillery.
has set his unholy foot on this land
to crush and humiliate the Maratha pride!
But we will show the Adilshahi
that the Marathas
cannot be reduced to ashes!
The Marathas soar like
phoenixes from the ashes!
Our blood rises to the occasion.
and today that moment has arrived.
Never forget!
No matter how mighty the enemy may be.
they can be defeated
with a single decisive strike!
I returned to my motherland
holding the finger of Ausaheb.
The ruins of Pune from that time
still haunt me.
Beyond that. what haunts me more
is the weeping eyes of an old lady
I once met.
I didn't just see Pune in those eyes.
I saw the entire Maratha motherland!
Those eyes screamed
the pain of broken houses.
vandalized temples.
devastated spirits.
and broken pride.
Those eyes of the old lady
are my Aausaheb's eyes.
Those are the eyes of your loving mothers.
Those eyes are the eyes
of Goddess Bhavani!
Those eyes ordain me to stand with pride.
ordain you. ordain all of us.
and ordain each and every Maratha!
Goddess Bhavani has ordained
this sword of mine!
This resolve is not for today.
but for a better tomorrow!
Let us pledge to the flame of this torch.
to erase the darkness of our
future generations. future clans.
and the future era!
All hail Goddess Bhavani!
Victory to Mother Goddess!
- Glory be to…
- Lord Mahadeva!
The meeting must be held in private.
Agreed.
Weapons to be allowed in the meeting.
Agreed. but no more than two guards
should be present in the shamiana.
Agreed.
A minimum of ten soldiers
is to be allowed for their protection.
Agreed. but their proximity
should be avoided.
They can be positioned within the
striking range of an arrow on both sides.
Agreed.
Commander Khan to arrive first
in the shamiana.
Not agreed.
Why should Commander Khan
wait for Shivaji Raje?
Let's avoid misunderstandings this time.
Commander Khan can inspect the shamiana
if he arrives early.
And traditionally speaking.
a disciple follows his guru.
I've never heard of a guru
following his disciple.
Agreed.
Netoji. be prepared with your
cavalry at Ambenali Ghat.
Uncle Kanhoji. keep a vigil on
Paarghat with the help of Deshmukhs.
Sure.
Tanaji. you have the responsibility
of the southwest of Pratapgad.
Bahirji. take control of the ghats.
Yes. my King.
Yesaji. Kaoji. you will accompany me.
Pant. the responsibility of bringing
Afzal to the shamiana is yours.
Jiva. under no circumstance
should you lose sight of Bada Sayyad.
Tomorrow. Siva will be
confined in this prison.
Dead or alive!
Your Highness. at last.
the elephant has decided to be a king!
Come what may.
Siva must not escape alive.
Yes. Your Highness.
Submit yourself in prostration.
and you'll be graced with the divine sight
of Vitthal and our King Shivaji as well!
Raje…
Everywhere. there is an echo of Siva.
Is he the one?
I have come across mentions of Afzal.
Your hospitality must be
appreciated. Siva.
The grandeur of this shamiana
surpasses even the court of Bijapur.
- Commander Khan. it is in your--
- I am not here to speak with you. Pant!
I had an image of you in my mind.
but you are shorter than I thought.
More than the Adilshahi Sultanate.
you think of me?
That is gratifying to hear.
Glory be to Allah!
I may think more of you.
but what is on your mind. Siva?
Swarajya.
Hail Shivrai!
Swarajya! Swarajya! Swarajya!
All along my journey.
I've only heard this!
What the hell is this
Swarajya nuisance all about?!
Be thoughtful in your choice of words.
If you ever fathom
the true essence of Swarajya.
you'll uphold the honor
of the saffron flag!
Hail Shivrai!
You're quite headstrong. Siva!
It was your insistence
that I should come here.
And it was my insistence
that I embrace you.
I accepted your insistence.
Now it's your turn to reciprocate.
Come. Siva. let me embrace you.
This is Afzal's clutch.
The more you resist.
the tighter the grip becomes!
This is the despicable status
of you Marathas!
This is the result of aspiring
beyond one's stature!
Henceforth. your Swarajya
will be nothing but a Deccan fable.
and no Maratha will dare
to dream of it again.
This is your end.
And with you.
this is the end of your Swarajya.
O Lord!
Mahadeva!
Give Shambhu my regards
and good wishes.
Arise and protect your own abode
The backstabbing nature of your ilk!
The day the Marathas awaken to this truth
will mark the beginning of your end!
Dawn of the Marathas!
Afzal. this is the true stature
of the Marathas!
The Marathas have ceased
to tolerate the backstabbers!
Raje…
Shivaji's legacy may end.
but Swarajya is eternal!
Raje…
Hindavi Swarajya shall be established.
This is the will of God!
Glory be to…
Mahadeva!
Raje…
The one and only one. zenith of valor
O Chhatrapati
O epitome of bravery. virtuous
Upholder of dharma. O Chhatrapati
O pride of Marathas
O tiger of Mother Goddess Bhavani
O legend of legends. righteous
Guardian of principles. O Chhatrapati
O fierce warrior
Crown jewel of Kshatriyas. O Chhatrapati
O pride of Marathas
O tiger of Mother Goddess Bhavani
- Glory to Bhavani!
- Glory to Shivaji!
Shivaji!
Jiva! Jiva!
Watch your words.
It is Shivaji Raje.
He's the ironclad shadow of Shivaji!
He's Jiva!
The ultimate enemy slayer!
He's the ironclad shadow of Shivaji!
He's Jiva!
The ultimate enemy slayer!
- Glory to Bhavani!
- Glory to Shivaji!
My King. you proceed.
You have reduced Ravana to dust.
I will burn the Lanka.
My King. Afzal has resolved to kill you.
To defeat a mighty enemy.
wisdom prevails over power!
Psyops are the first weapons
to strike the enemy.
- Bad omen!
Two steps back in the present
mean one step forward in the future.
How many forts and pilgrim houses
are there on his route?
Five.
Concede them with minimal resistance.
The forts were deserted
before we could reach them.
Afzal's terror arrives
before Afzal himself.
- Glory be to…
- Lord Mahadeva!
Convert your enemies'
confidence into arrogance.
- Raje has heard that…
- You have unmatched strength.
The mere thought of you is a nightmare.
He believes there is one
and only one stalwart in Bijapur.
Commander Afzal Khan!
When war is inevitable. we must
choose the battlefield to our advantage.
Pant. design a clever plan.
Commander Khan must come to Jawali
to resolve this deadlock. Krushnaji.
I will come to Jawali!
- Glory to Bhavani!
- Glory to Shivaji!
- Glory be to…
- Lord Mahadeva!
Promise to bring me Afzal's head. Shivba.
Raje…
Jagadamba!
This is not just a seal. With it.
I pass on the dream of Swarajya.
I feel…
my lifetime is not enough
to achieve this grand dream.
Greatest of all warriors!
Crown jewel of the Kshatriya clan!
Sovereign of the throne!
The king of kings!
Victory to His Majesty.
His Highness. His Holiness
Chhatrapati Shivaji Maharaj!
All hail!
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm